<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>software architecture on Security engineering by vixentael</title><link>https://vixentael.dev/categories/software-architecture/</link><description>Recent content in software architecture on Security engineering by vixentael</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vixentael.dev/categories/software-architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Maintaining cryptographic library for 12 languages</title><link>https://vixentael.dev/talks/maintaining-crypto-lib-for-12languages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vixentael.dev/talks/maintaining-crypto-lib-for-12languages/</guid><description>Maintaining cross-platform cryptographic library is a journey full of unexpected bugs, language-specific hacks, difficult decisions and endless struggle to make developer-facing APIs easy-to-use and hard-to-misuse.</description></item><item><title>Defense in depth: trench warfare principles for building secure distributed applications</title><link>https://vixentael.dev/talks/defense-in-depth-data-2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vixentael.dev/talks/defense-in-depth-data-2019/</guid><description>It comes to no surprise that any micro-services, any security controls you use to build applications – will eventually be broken (or fail).</description></item><item><title>Protecting sensitive data in modern multi-component systems</title><link>https://vixentael.dev/talks/protecting-data-in-multi-component-systems/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vixentael.dev/talks/protecting-data-in-multi-component-systems/</guid><description>Modern apps are multi-components, and most data leaks are caused by poor architectural decisions.</description></item><item><title>Encryption without magic, risk management without pain</title><link>https://vixentael.dev/talks/encryption-without-magic-risk-management-without-pain/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vixentael.dev/talks/encryption-without-magic-risk-management-without-pain/</guid><description>In-depth technical inquiry about application-level encryption. How crypto helps to narrow down significant risks to controlled attack surfaces, enables managing the risk efficiently and elegantly, how tools and algorithms sit in a broader context of managing infrastructure-wide risks associated with handling sensitive data.</description></item></channel></rss>